(サスケ)香燐！ 目をさませ香燐！
Karin! Wake up! Karin!
しっかりしろ！
すぐに医療班を呼んでやる！
Hang in there!
I'll get the Medical Corps
right away!
(香燐)ああ サスケ…。
サスケ もういいんだ。
Sasuke, Sasuke, it's okay...
もう だから➡
It's too—
It's okay... So please...
だから お願いだ…。
Please...
ねぇ サスケ。 お願いだから…。
Okay?
Sasuke, please... smile.
笑ってよ サスケ。
Smile, Sasuke.
あのときみたいに。
Like that one time.
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
To See That Smile, Just One More Time
No!
(香燐)ダメ！
香燐…。
Karin...
具合が悪いって
言ってたじゃない！
You said you didn't feel well.
Hurry up!
(ゾウスイ)早くしろ。
We have to help out.
力を貸すのが この里に
置いてもらう条件だもの。
It's the requirement for us
being allowed to stay here.
だけど！
But!
I'll be right back.
すぐに戻るから。
(香燐)やだ！
No!
いい子にしていてね。
(香燐)母さん！
Be a good girl.
Mom!
母さん！
母さん…。
Mom...
立て！
Stand up.
MEDICAL
HIDDEN GRASS HOSPITAL
(香燐)ここは？
Where are we?
We took huge losses
from a surprise attack.
(ゾウスイ)奇襲により我々は
多大な被害をこうむった。
The village is overflowing
with the wounded.
里は今
負傷者であふれかえっている。
We won't make it with
just your mother.
お前の母だけでは 間に合わない。
(香燐)母さん!?
Mom?!
うええっ！
Let me go!
離して！ 母さんが… 母さんが！
My mom...!
My mom is—!
There was no other choice
in order to protect the village!
里を守るには
こうするしかなかったのだ。
What—?!
It's unfortunate that
you lost your mother,
(ゾウスイ)お前の母を失ったのは
残念だが➡
but we still have more wounded.
まだ ケガ人が残っている。
遅いぞ！ あの女は どうした？
You're late!
Where's that woman?
She's dead.
死んだ。 今日から
こいつが あとを継ぐ。
She's going to take over
from today.
Huh?!
え!?
こんなガキが？ 大丈夫なのか？
This child? Can she handle it?
She is that woman's daughter.
あの女の娘だ。
同じ能力を持っている。
She has the same ability.
No!
嫌… 離して！ 嫌ぁ！
Let me go!
No!
We're letting you stay
行き場のないやつを
置いてやってるんだ。
because you have
nowhere else to go.
Work enough to earn your stay!
食いぶち分くらいは
働いてもらわんとな。
It hurts!
いてえ！ チクショウ… いてえよぉ…。
Damn it! It hurts!
Don't worry!
大丈夫だ すぐ治してやるからな。
We'll heal you in no time.
No!
嫌ぁ!!
さぁ 噛むんだ！
Now go on, bite!
Please... stop.
お願い… やめて…。
We took your mother
to your house.
お前の母は 家に運んでおいた。
From tomorrow,
明日からは 呼ばれずとも
病院で待機しておくように。
go to the hospital even
if no one comes to get you.
Over there! Send more chakra!
そっち！ チャクラをもっと送れ！
そいつは もういい。 無駄だ！
Forget him! It's too late.
check the one next to him.
隣を診てやれ！
もたもたするな！ 来い！
Don't dawdle! Come with me!
そっちは 薬で間に合う！
よし そのまま続けろ。
That one can be treated
with medicine.
Continue just like that.
今度は こっちだ！ 早く来い！
Now this one!
Hurry and come with me!
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…。
Hey, you have work to do!
(ゾウスイ)おい！ 仕事だ！
ヒッ！
こんなところで立ち止まるな！
Don't stop here!
でも うち 戦場なんて…。
But I've never been
on a battlefield...
Shut up!
黙れ！
走らなければ➡
If you can't run, I'll kill you.
俺がお前を殺す！
え… うっ…。
Stand!
立て！
あぁ…。
Go.
行け！
え？
さぁ！
Come on!
Mom...
母さん…。
The higher-ups have decided
to let you take part
上層部の話し合いで➡
お前を次の中忍試験に
参加させることになった。
in the next Chunin Exams.
Me?
うちを？
この試験は➡
This exam displays the strength
参加した下忍の実力をもって
各忍里の力をはかる。
of each Ninja Village through
their genin's abilities.
It's considered a war by proxy.
代理戦争の側面を持つ➡
We cannot afford to lose.
我々としては
負けるわけにはいかんのだ。
Your duty is to keep the other two
completely replenished.
(ゾウスイ)お前の役目は
他の２人の徹底回復。
We took in an outsider like you...
よそ者の身で養われてきたのだ➡
Keep that in mind and make sure
you get us good results.
そのことを肝に銘じて
必ず結果を出せ。
はい…。
Yes.
NO TRESPASSING
Damn it... They're all monsters!
チクショウ！
どいつもこいつも化けものか！
How can we steal a scroll
奪うどころか 自分らの巻物を
守るだけでも精一杯とは。
when defending ours
takes everything we've got?
But we can't back off!
だからって むざむざ引けるか。
The honor of our village rests with us!
俺たちには
里の威信がかかっている。
なら もう一度 追尾をかけるか。
Then we'll go back to tracking.
And we'll definitely
get it done this time.
次こそしとめるんだ！
うっ！
う うちは何をすれば…。
What should I do?
You'll only be in the way
if you come along.
ついて来られても足手まといだ。
これを持って隠れてろ。
(香燐)はい。
Take this and stay hidden.
Okay.
あっ うぅっ！
あっ 隠れてなきゃ…。
Oh yeah.
I have to keep hiding.
うっ…。
あっ！
Lions Barrage!
獅子連弾！
The Earth Scroll... same as us.
俺たちと同じ地の書か。
《あっ メ メガネ…》
My glasses!
Later.
じゃあな。
MEDICAL
HIDDEN GRASS HOSPITAL
You've been such
a disappointment.
お前には 失望させられたものだ。
I hoped for better results
than this!
もう少し マシな結果になるかと
思っていたがな。
I guess you're just an outsider...
しょせんは よそ者。
so you don't feel any loyalty
for the village.
里への忠誠など
望むべくもないということか。
That's not true! I—!
そんな… うちは。
Then prove it.
ならば 証明してみせろ。
Hurry to the north fortress.
北の砦へと発つがいい。
北の砦？
North fortress?
The fighting's raging there.
激戦区だ。
北の砦とは ご苦労なことだ。
The north fortress?
Of all missions...
That place is teeming
with the Kaguya Clan.
あの辺りは最近 かぐや一族が
流れ込んでいるからな。
殺戮にしか興味のない
とんでもない連中だ。
They're a terrible, bloodthirsty bunch.
So far, the north fortress
is keeping them at bay, but...
北の砦が
防波堤になってはいるが…。
Yeah...
ああ
ひどいことになってるって話だ。
I hear this is going to get real ugly.
You're going to be a great help.
助かるわ
戦闘員だって無限じゃないもの。
There are only so many fighters.
But with you here,
they'll heal much faster, right?
でも あなたがいれば➡
彼らを速やかに
回復できるのよね？
早速 始めてちょうだい。
Please start right away.
あ… でも。
Oh, but...
I should have known
an outsider wouldn't...
やっぱり よそ者は…。
あっ。
What amazing dedication!
すばらしい献身だわ。
Hey, everyone...
あなたたち！
外の患者も順番に運んできて！
Bring in the wounded
from outside one by one.
え…。
I can't go on...
《香燐 : もう無理…
ここにいては死ぬ》
If I stay here... I'll die.
あっ… あぁ～！
キャー！ 助けて！
Help me!
I'll bet this redhead is a remnant
of the clan from the Hidden Eddy...
この赤い髪 渦潮の生き残りに
間違いなさそうだ。
You were right when you said
she'd be worth something.
小遣い稼ぎに寄って正解だったな。
(２人)ヘッヘッヘ…。
A shinobi without a homeland
is quite tragic.
(大蛇丸)故郷をなくした忍
っていうのは➡
哀れなものね。
でもね
どうせなら自分で決めなさい。
But, you know...
You must decide for yourself.
私のもとに来れば もう誰も
あなたに手は出せないわ。
If you come with me,
no one will ever touch you again.
You're Karin?
(カブト)キミが香燐だね？
大蛇丸様から話は聞いてるよ。
The one Lord Orochimaru mentioned?
I understand you have
an unusual power.
なんでも珍しい力があるとか。
So... where is Lord Orochimaru?
あの 大蛇丸様は？
He's a very busy man.
(カブト)あの方は
お忙しい方だからね。
So you're assigned to me.
Come with me.
基本的には キミは
僕の下につくことになる。
おいで。
Who are these people?
(香燐)この人たちは？
We use them for experiments.
実験に使うんだ。
The research Lord Orochimaru is
conducting requires a lot of data.
大蛇丸様が進めている研究には➡
たくさんのデータがいるからね。
僕は それをキミにも
手伝ってほしいと考えている。
I'm thinking that
you can help with that.
Okay, here we are.
さあ 着いたよ。
彼は実験中のサンプルだ。
He was the subject
of an experiment,
but we're in a bind
because he's gotten so weak.
弱ってしまって困っていたんだよ。
I also want to see your power.
キミの力も見ておきたいしね。 さあ。
Okay...
うわ～！ キャー！
(カブト)ふ～ん こいつはすごい。
That's quite amazing!
さすが 大蛇丸様に
見込まれただけのことはある。
Leave it to Lord Orochimaru
to see your potential...
これからもよろしく頼むよ。
I'm counting on your help.
(香憐)ここは？
(カブト)北アジト。
Where are we?
The Northern Hideout...
今までのとは規模も設備も桁違い。
The old place doesn't compare
with this one in scale and set-up.
本格的な人体実験場だよ。
This is what you would call
a real experimental laboratory.
今日からしばらく キミには
重吾の実験を手伝ってもらうよ。
From today,
you'll be helping
with the experiments
on Jugo for a while.
Jugo?
重吾？
(カブト)呪印唯一のオリジナル。
Jugo... the one and only
killing machine of the Curse Mark.
殺人鬼の重吾だよ。
あっ あぁ…。
Karin, you did well.
香憐 よく頑張ってくれたわね。
おかげで重吾の体液からの酵素も
完成したわ。
Thanks to you,
I was able to perfect an enzyme
from Jugo's bodily fluids.
So, how about it?
どう？ あなたしだいだけど。
It's up to you, but would you like
to be in charge of this place?
ここを仕切ってみる気は
ないかしら？
Lord Orochimaru...
大蛇丸様…。
あなたも苦労してきたでしょ？
You've been through
many hardships.
You should stay here
and take it easy for a while.
しばらく ここで
体を休めるといいわ。
もったいないお言葉。
I'm humbled by those words.
若輩者ですが➡
Though I'm still young
and inexperienced,
I'll do anything you ask of me,
Lord Orochimaru.
大蛇丸様のため
務めさせていただきます。
Please excuse me.
失礼します。
《これで… うちもやっと》
Now... I'll finally...
Number 97 is scheduled
for surgery this afternoon.
今日は午後から97番の手術がある。
ちょっとハードになるから
付き添いを頼むよ。
It will be difficult,
but I want you to assist.
I got it.
わかっている。
死なせなければいいんだろ？
I just have to keep him
from dying, right?
Exactly.
(カブト)そういうことだね。
あれは？
Who is that?
Oh, that's Sasuke.
あぁ サスケ君だよ。
He's Lord Orochimaru's favorite.
大蛇丸様の
いちばんのお気に入りさ。
He's a bit strange.
彼は ちょっと変わっていてね➡
He sought us out in order to
become strong for a certain goal.
目的を果たす力を手に入れるため
自ら進んで ここに来たのさ。
"A goal?"
(香燐)目的？
But he probably won't fulfill it.
(カブト)だが
おそらく それは果たされない。
He's destined to be
Lord Orochimaru's next vessel.
彼は 大蛇丸様の
次の器になる運命だからね。
ふ～ん…。
I am... the one who will unravel
the mysterious of this world!
(大蛇丸)私は
この世を解き明かす者…。
I am the one
who will receive everything!
すべてを手にする者な…。
So it was you after all, Sasuke.
やっぱり あんたか… サスケ。
Karin, come with me. I need you.
香燐 ついて来い。 お前が必要だ。
Huh? Why would I follow you?
はぁ!? なんで お前なんかに！
うちは ここを任されてんだよ！
I'm under orders
to oversee this place!
Orochimaru is gone.
大蛇丸は もういない。
Suigetsu, release everyone held
prisoner here in this hideout.
水月 このアジトに
捕らえられてるやつらを➡
全員 解放しろ。
なっ…。
What—?!
ハァ… 相変わらず命令口調だな。
As usual, ordering people around...
You can't just come here
and take over!
勝手なことすんじゃねえよ！
You don't know what it took
to keep things in order here...
私が どんだけ苦労して
ここをシメてきたか！
Without prisoners, there won't be
any need for a warden.
囚人がいなけりゃ
監視役も必要なくなるわけだ。
I'll say it once more.
Come with me, Karin.
もう一度 言う。
俺についてこい。 香燐。
What will you do?
どうする？
Sasuke!
サスケ！
This is bad...
やばい…。
Here, Sasuke...
Hurry up and bite me!
ほら サスケ
さっさとうちに噛みつけ。
Do it now!
ほら 早く！
ああ～ん！
(ダンゾウ)がは…。
く…。
サスケ！
Sasuke!
Are you all right?
大丈夫か!?
ほら さっさと噛め！
Hurry and bite!
ああっ…。
Karin, Suigetsu, Jugo...
香燐 水月 重吾…。
Thanks to your help,
お前たちのおかげで➡
I was able to bring down
Danzo the Hokage.
火影であるダンゾウを
倒すことができた。
But my goal now is
to destroy the Hidden Leaf,
だが 俺の目的は
今の木ノ葉を倒し➡
become the Hokage and build
a new Hidden Leaf Village.
俺が火影となって
新しい木ノ葉を作ること…。
This is the critical moment.
ここからが正念場だ。
How is the war going?
The same...
戦況は？
(水月)相変わらずだよ。
They're such jerks.
ったく 嫌な連中だよ。
Taking advantage of the chaos
サスケが火影になった混乱に乗じて
攻めてくるなんてさ。
from you becoming
the Hokage to attack...
Bad news. Karin's been...
(重吾)大変だ 香燐が…。
I thought you were a spy
from the Leaf.
(ゾウスイ)木ノ葉の
ネズミかと思ったが…。
But we've stumbled across
someone very interesting.
おもしろいやつと
出くわしたものだ…。
Do you know her?
知り合いですか？
Long ago, the Grass took
in this wanderer.
昔 草で飼っていた流れ者だ。
If you bite into her and
suck out her chakra,
噛みついてチャクラを吸えば➡
it will heal every kind of wound.
どんな傷でも
回復させることができる。
Hey! Take her to the medical tent!
おい！ こいつを
医療班のテントへ連れていけ！
Stop!
I don't care if it kills her.
やめろ！
死んでもかまわん！
She betrayed the people
she was indebted to!
恩ある里に 牙を剥いた報いだ。
Suck out every ounce of chakra
until she dies!
命尽きるまで 吸い尽くしてやれ！
う… うわ… あ…。
Karin! Wake up, Karin!
香燐！ 目をさませ 香燐！
Hang in there!
しっかりしろ！
すぐに医療班を呼んでやる！
I'll go get the Medical unit now!
Sasuke... Sasuke...
(香燐)ああ… サスケ… サスケ…。
It's okay... it's too—
もう いいんだ…。
もう… だから お願いだ…。
I just have one favor to ask...
Please, Sasuke...
ねえ サスケ… お願いだから…。
Please smile... Sasuke.
笑ってよ サスケ…。
terase asu wo ima kokoro tsutau messeeji
Shine a light, tomorrow is now,
a message straight to the heart
boku to yoku ni ta itami uchiake te kure ta hito
Hearing someone tell me about
the same kind of pain I have
futo hitori ja nain datte omoetan da
Made me think that I'm not alone
dakedo nagareta namida kamishime ta nukumori o
But the flowing tears and the warmth I relished
itsumade mo boku wa dakishimete ireru ka na?
How long can those envelop me?
kizutsui te kizutsui te nai te nai te tsuyoku nare subete
Hurting again and again,
crying over and over gives you strength for everything
me ni utsuru sono keshiki wa eien ni tada kokoro e to
That scenery you see goes straight to the heart,
massugu tsunagatte iku
now and forever
hanate niji no sora omoi nara koko ni aru (my heart)
Let it go, the rainbow sky, my wishes are here (My heart)
terase asu wo ima kokoro tsutau messeeji
Shine a light, tomorrow is now,
a message straight to the heart
hanate niji no sora
Let it go, the rainbow sky
The next episode is the first
of Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero!
Grandma Tsunade is under
the Infinite Tsukuyomi.
今回は 特別企画➡
In her dream she reads
a story Pervy Sage left behind.
皆さんからのリクエストに
お応えいたします。
And, the protagonist
in the story is...
最初はこの曲 『皆の衆』。
M-Me?
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Loser Ninja."
The protagonist, is a loser?